《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
怪物要来了  市长先生
Monsters are coming, Mr. Mayor.
他们将净化这座城市
Who will cleanse this city.
如果你把公司卖给我
If you sell me your company,
我就把杀死你父母的凶手的名字告诉你
I will give you the name of the man who killed your parents.
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是布鲁斯的朋友
I'm Bruce's friend.
而你就是个下贱胚子
And you're a piece of gutter trash.
而你觉得那只小狐狸精
And you think that little minx
会告诉你吗
is gonna tell you something, do you?
要从那样的女孩口中套取信息
Getting information out of a girl like that
需要一定程度的骗术
requires a level of deception
目前你还没那个本事
that you do not yet possess.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
我能问问罪名是什么吗
May I ask what the charge is?
绑架折磨奥布雷·詹姆斯
The kidnapping and torture of Aubrey James.
这是柯林格小姐的
These were Ms. Kringle's.
一个人没有任何所爱  就是自由的
A man with nothing to love is free.
帕克斯  你今天干得很棒
Parks...you did good today.
爱德华多·弗拉明戈杀了帕克斯警官
Eduardo Flamingo killed Officer Parks
然后才被制服关起来
before they could get him into lockup.
布鲁斯·韦恩必死无疑
Bruce Wayne will die,
他的公司将归我们
and his company will be ours.
现在已经万事俱备了
Everything is ready.
兄弟们即将到来
The brothers' arrival is imminent.
哥谭将在鲜血中得到救赎
Gotham will be redeemed in blood.
-求求你不要伤害我  -闭嘴
- Please don't hurt me! - Shut up.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 辰星晓Reginamoon   小胖纸Amy   Silence   盐湖凉开水
翻译 DustD   木浅   charcie   大K   小酸奶!   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
忘带伞了吗
Forget your umbrella?
我还以为探视时间已经过了呢
Thought visiting hours were over.
可对逮捕了哥谭市长的人  规矩算什么呢
What are rules to the man who arrested the mayor of Gotham?
能告诉我你的来访是为何事吗
Any chance you're gonna tell me what this little visit is about?
也许是为了明天的听证
Tomorrow's hearing, perhaps?
你是来幸灾乐祸的
You're here to gloat.
听过凯瑟琳·帕克斯这个名字吗
Does the name Katherine Parks mean anything to you?
没  没听说过
No, can't say it does.
我明天会到场的
I'm gonna be there tomorrow.
去看他们给你判刑
I'm gonna watch them put you away.
很高兴见到你  警探
Always a pleasure, Detective.
你都湿透了
You're soaking wet.
想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
凯瑟琳·帕克斯才23岁
Katherine Parks was 23.
刚入警队一年
On the force a year.
而今天我们为她举行了葬礼
And today we put her in the ground
因为当我有机会时
because when I had the chance,
我没采取唯一明智的做法
I didn't do the only sensible thing.
吉姆...
Jim...
一个杀手杀了四名警察
An assassin kills four cops...
挑衅我  看我敢不敢开枪  而我没开
dares me to pull the trigger, and I don't.
你来解释解释啊
Explain that to me.
那人是你的犯人  你别无选择
That man was your prisoner; you didn't have a choice.
我有选择的
I had a choice.
是啊  要么维护法律
Yes, to uphold the law
要么成为一个凶手
or to become a murderer.
你的选择是正确的
You made the right one.
你觉得凯瑟琳·帕克斯也会这么想吗
You think Katherine Parks feels the same way?
她的家人呢
What about her family?
我今天去见盖勒文了
I went to see Galavan today.
然后呢
And?
你是问我有没有让看守把摄像头关掉吗
You're asking did I get the guards to turn the cameras off?
没有  但他们会愿意的
No. But they would have.
盖勒文相当于是杀了帕克斯  艾森
Galavan as good as killed Parks, Essen
以及其他一堆警察
and a dozen other cops,
但他却好好地坐在那里
and yet he sits there,
还笑着  呼吸着
smiling, breathing.
而明天  奥布雷·詹姆斯就会在大陪审团前
And tomorrow, Aubrey James is going in front of the grand jury
告诉他们他被盖勒文绑架并折磨
and telling them that he was kidnapped and tortured by Galavan.
-他会被关很久的  -也许吧
- He's gonna be put away for a long time. - Maybe.
但是他那副样子
Just the way he acted.
不像是一个面临十年牢狱之灾的人
It wasn't a man looking at a decade in prison.
我有种不好的预感
I have a bad feeling.
吉姆  已经结束了
Jim, it's over.
你干得很好
You did good.
来睡吧
Now, come to bed.
这是医嘱
Doctor's orders.
我在哪
Where am I?
你是谁
Who are you?
审判日即将来临
The day of reckoning is at hand.
九人之血
And the blood of the nine
将洗刷罪孽
shall wash away the sin.
不要
Please!
哥谭将得到净化
And Gotham will be cleansed.
哥谭
第二季  第十集
这行不通的
This isn't gonna work.
这姑娘是来自一流骗子家族的一流骗子
This girl is a world-class liar from a family of world-class liars.
她会看穿你的  不然她叔叔也会
She'll see through you. Or her uncle will.
那很有可能
Well, that's very possible.
所以呢
And?
布鲁斯  他们假装对你友好
Bruce, they're playing nice with you
是因为他们觉得你信任他们
because they think you trust them.
一旦他们发现你不信任他们了
Once they see you don't,
马上就会翻脸
it'll get ugly fast.
你说的都对  塞琳娜
Your logic is flawless, Selina.
现在还不算晚...
It's not too late...
即使有一丝可能盖勒文知道
If there's even a chance Galavan knows
是谁杀了我父母  我都得试试
who killed my parents, I have to take it.
我和阿尔弗雷德说我放学后要练习击剑
I told Alfred I have fencing practice after school
这可以为我们争取点时间
to buy us some time if we need it.
最好的骗子  总是说真话
The best liars always tell the truth.
记住了
Something to remember.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那是她的车  你赶紧...
That's her car. You'd b...
阿尔瓦雷斯  打电话给停尸房
Alvarez, call the morgue.
问问有没有与格特鲁德·科波特特征相符的尸体
See if any bodies turned up matching Gertrude Cobblepot.
她并不是凭空消失了  盖勒文杀了她
She didn't just vanish; Galavan killed her.
昨天已经核实过了
Did that yesterday.
那你今天再核实一遍
And you're gonna do it again today.
我自己也有案子  戈登
I got my own cases, Gordon.
在顶层公寓发现的那个标志有查到什么吗
Turn up anything on that symbol we found in the penthouse?
没呢  我在等圣巴特教堂的麦克神父回话
No. I'm waiting for Father Mike up at St. Bart's.
袍子的照片也发了他一份
Sent him a picture of the cassock, too.
他很了解那些宗教玩意儿
He's up on all that religious mumbo-jumbo.
我们到底想找什么
What exactly are we after here?
将盖勒文与艾森  帕克斯
Something tying Galavan to the murders
和其他人被杀关联起来的证据
of Essen, Parks, any of the people he killed.
这话有点多余  吉姆  但他要进监狱了
Not to state the obvious, Jim, but the guy's going to jail.
-我昨天去见他了  -是吗
- I went to see him last night. - Yeah?
让守卫关摄像头了吗
Get the guards to turn off the camera?
他脸上的表情  哈维...
The look on his face, Harvey...
说不好  我无法形容
I don't know, I can't describe it.
开什么玩笑
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
天哪
God...
他都被刺伤了
Guy gets stabbed;
我以为我们至少能太平一周呢
I thought we'd have at least a week of peace.
警监  你怎么样  收到我送的花了吗
Hey, Cap! How you doing? Did you get my flowers?
警监  您怎么样
Captain, how you feeling?
还行
Eh, five-by-five.
如果我不说话  那医生就会让我躺一周
Damn doc would've had me in bed a week if I'd have let him.
有案子给你
Got something for you.
巡警在码头发现了一具尸体
Unis found a dead body down by the port,
喉咙从左到右被切开
throat cut from ear to ear.
虽然死者是人渣  但工作还是要做
The vic's a career dirtbag, but the work's the same.
长官  如果没关系  我想继续查盖勒文
Uh, sir, if it's all the same, I'd like to stay on Galavan.
不行  盖勒文完蛋了
It isn't. Galavan's cooked,
所以要继续给你安排工作  怎么了
so you're back in the rotation. What?
我只是觉得我们遗漏了什么  长官
I just feel like we're missing something, sir.
疑团的一部分
There's some piece of the puzzle
最终会让我们措手不及
that's gonna come back and bite us.
再给我几天时间
Just give me a few more days.
不行
Answer's no.
尽管生气吧  但这是为你好
Be pissed, but it's for your own good.
还有
Oh, and, uh...
帕克斯的事很遗憾
I'm sorry about Parks.
她不该那样惨死
She deserved better.
吉姆
Yo, Jim!
麦克神父发来消息
Message from Father Mike.
那标志是
That symbol is from something
圣杜马修会的
called the Order of St. Dumas.
他们以前在市中心有间修道院
They used to have an abbey downtown.
巴恩斯刚刚叫我别再追查盖勒文
Barnes just told me to lay off of Galavan.
那你可能不会在乎
Well, then you probably don't care
市长办公室上周想买下那间修道院
that the mayor's office tried to buy the abbey last week.
-盖勒文想买下它  -是的
- Galavan tried to buy it? - Yeah.
以城市开发作借口
Some urban development nonsense.
新业主拒绝了
New owners said no.
那儿现在是华人按摩院
It's a Chinese slap-slap joint now.
管他呢  你拿到地址了吗
Hell with it. You got the address?
拿到了  去沾沾桃花运吧
Yep. Let's go get lucky.
你叔叔曾向我提议  以杀害我父母凶手的名字
Your uncle made me an offer: the name of my parents' killer
交换我把我韦恩集团的股份卖给他
in exchange for selling him my shares in Wayne Enterprises.
我拒绝了
I said no.
但现在情况变了
But circumstances have changed.
你要卖给他吗
You're going to sell?
不
No.
-那  -你叔叔被捕了  资产也遭冻结
- Then... - Your uncle was arrested, and his assets are frozen.
告诉他我会帮他支付辩护费  作为交换
Tell him I'll pay for his defense; in exchange,
他把名字告诉我
he gives me the name.
你在趁火打劫
You're taking advantage of him.
我们相互手握对方所需  仅此而已
I have something he needs, he has something I need, that's all.
你相信人们说他的那些话吗
Do you believe what people are saying about him?
我不在乎人们怎么说
I don't care what people say.
我父亲本来正在调查韦恩集团
My father was investigating Wayne Enterprises,
然后他和我母亲就遭人杀害
then he and my mother were killed.
去年  我也调查了韦恩集团
Last year, I investigated Wayne Enterprises,
然后有人企图杀阿尔弗雷德
and someone tried to kill Alfred.
我必须找出杀死我父母的凶手
Either I find out who killed my parents
并阻止公司的罪行  不然我就死定了
and stop whatever's happening in my company, or I'm dead.
我需要那个名字
I need that name.
大陪审团听证会就在今天
The grand jury hearing is today.
他会被无罪释放的
He's going to be cleared.
如果他没有呢
What if he's not?
那怎么办
What then?
茜尔薇  让他把那个名字告诉你
Silver, get him to tell you the name,
我会保证他可以得到最好的辩护
and I will make sure he has the best defense money can buy,
我保证
I promise.
既然你觉得他有罪
You think he's guilty.
那为什么还相信他说的话呢
Why would you believe anything he says?
因为是由你来告诉我
Because it would come from you.
如果是你告诉我那个名字  我就知道是真的
If you bring me the name, I'll know it's real.
你真这么想吗
Do you mean that?
我见过他后就给你打电话
I'll call you after I talk to him.
还是得拿到名字
Still got to get the name.
我会的  我上学要迟到了
I will. I'm late for school.
不到时候
Not yet.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
看起来不像个按摩院啊
Doesn't look much like a massage parlor.
可能还有其他入口吧
Maybe there's another entrance.
让这些女孩快走
Get these girls out of here.
快走  快  快点
Come on, come on. Come on.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
先生
Sir?
站住
Stop!
把刀放下
Drop the knife.
审判日即将来临
The day of reckoning is at hand,
九人之血将洗刷罪孽
and the blood of nine shall wash away the sin.
你是谁
Who are you?
你与盖勒文有什么关系
What's your connection to Galavan?
哥谭将得到净化
And Gotham shall be cleansed.
按摩院的女孩说她们看到至少六个僧侣
The girls at the parlor say they saw at least six monks.
他们一定也是这个圣杜马修会的
They have to be a part of this same Order of St. Dumas.
布洛克的线人说他们是苦行僧
Bullock's contact says they're penitents.
嗯  我把字典落在包包里了
Yeah, I forgot my dictionary in my purse.
他们相信通过痛苦来净化心灵
They believed in purification through pain.
鲜血
Blood.
他们曾在哥谭盛极一时
They were big in the old days in Gotham.
然后在大约一百年前突然消失了
Then about a hundred years ago, vanished.
我们在盖勒文的顶层公寓里找到的就是他们的纹章
It was their crest we found in Galavan's penthouse.
现在他们回来了  发现自己的
And now they're back and they're pissed off
老窝变成了高级妓院  就勃然大怒
that their home is a high-end rub-and-tug joint.
好吧
Fine.
把你掌握的整理一下交给阿尔瓦雷斯
Gather what you have and give it to Alvarez.
警监  这些僧侣可能是
Captain, these monks could be the key
盖勒文计划的关键
to whatever Galavan is planning.
我记得我已经给了你一个案子  警探
As I recall, Detective, I already gave you a case.
而且我还特别嘱咐你
And I expressly told you
别再纠结盖勒文
to move away from Galavan.
港口那个死人
The dead guy at the ports--
他昨天在城市另一头袭击了一位女士
he attacked a woman across town yesterday.
在她的证词中  她说袭击她的人被一群
In her statement, she said her attacker was pulled off
穿着僧侣袍的人拽走了
by a man dressed like a monk.
宇宙总这么喜欢你吗  警探
Does the universe normally like you this much, Detective?
这是头一次
First time.
好吧  就算是同一批僧侣
All right, say they're the same monks.
他们为什么要杀掉一群银行家和一个...
Why would they kill a bunch of bankers and some...
无名的街头混混
nobody street thug?
那僧侣说
The monk said,
"九人之血将洗刷罪孽"
"The blood of the nine shall wash away the sin."
显然是某种仪式
It's obviously some sort of ritual.
如果盖勒文也牵扯其中
And if Galavan is connected,
他能从中得到什么好处
what does he stand to gain?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们得找到一个僧侣让他告诉我们
We have to find a monk and get him to talk.
考虑到上一个做了什么
Well, considering what this last one did,
这可能没那么容易
that might not be so easy.
警监  这事发生在
Captain, it's no coincidence
盖勒文即将受审的时候  绝不是巧合
that this is happening just as Galavan's about to stand trial.
不管是什么  今天就会发生了
Whatever it is, it's going down today.
"九人之血"
"The blood of the nine."
已经死了五个
Five are already dead.
好吧
Okay.
但我依然要你去听詹姆斯向大陪审团作证
But I still want you at the grand jury to hear James' testimony.
还有  戈登  不管是什么阴谋
And, Gordon, whatever this is,
阻止它
stop it.
布鲁斯  是茜尔薇
Bruce, it's Silver.
我刚见过了我叔叔
I just saw my uncle.
他同意了你的条件
He agreed to your deal.
你的所有要求
Everything you asked.
他把名字告诉了我  布鲁斯
He... he told me the name, Bruce.
放学后到街对面见我
Meet me across the way after school.
别喊  别跑
Don't scream. Don't run.
上车就是
Just get in.
不然我们杀了这女孩
Or we kill the girl.
走吧
Go.
这疤痕组织很老
The scar tissue's old.
看到伤口越过了他的肩膀吗
See how the wounds wrap over his shoulder?
这绝对是他自己弄的
It was definitely self-inflicted.
我捅了他  他丝毫没退缩
I stabbed him, he didn't flinch.
他手掌上还有很厚伤痕
And there are thick scars on the palms.
他曾反复地划伤自己
He cut himself there repeatedly.
麦克神父说领袖们会割伤自己
Father Mike said the leaders cut themselves
用血标记追随者  算是赐福
and then mark the followers with the blood, like a blessing.
真好
Charming.
又找到这三天内发现的另两具尸体
Dug up two more bodies from the past three days.
都是职业罪犯
Career hoods.
死后被弃尸  都是割喉
Killed somewhere, then dumped-- both their throats cut.
死了七个
Seven down,
还剩两个
two to go.
好奇怪
It's weird.
为什么之前没一个人见过这些僧侣呢
How has nobody seen these monks till now?
首先  他们杀人后  远距离弃尸
A, they're killing people and carrying them across town,
其次  他们是僧侣啊
and B, they're monks.
昨天遭袭的那个女人
The woman who was attacked yesterday,
她说僧侣和袭击者
she said the monk vanished
一起消失了  但是
with the attacker, but...
那小巷是个死胡同
that alley was a dead end.
下水道
The sewers.
不要
Oh, no.
僧侣将袭击了那女子的人拽进了
So, the monk drags the woman's attacker
我们头上的小巷
into the alley above us.
接下来  他就喂海鸥了
Next thing, he's food for seagulls.
港口在这边
Ports are this way.
又来
Again?
有没有摇摇把手试试
Did you try jiggling the handle?
你往里面放什么了
Well, what did you put down it?
汤普金斯医生  有什么事吗
Dr. Thompkins, can I help you?
爱德  这是死掉僧侣的尸检报告
Hi, Ed. This is the autopsy on the dead monk.
吉姆要你做个毒检
Jim wants you to run toxicology.
真有趣
Fascinating.
那种想要自虐的冲动
The need to inflict that kind of pain on oneself.
还有事吗
Is there anything else?
没了
No.
其实有
Yes.
你刚才是在和柯丽丝汀通话吗
Was that Kristen you were just talking to?
什么
What?
抱歉  你听起来像是在和
Oh, sorry. It sounded like you were talking
你家里的人讲话  你家除了她
to somebody in your apartment, and who besides...
我是在和水管工说话
I was talking to my plumber.
你有跟柯丽丝汀联系吗
Well, have you heard from Kristen?
我知道她说她病了  我想去看看她
I know she said she was sick. I was thinking of stopping by...
其实  她没病
As it happens, she's not sick.
她说了谎
She lied.
骗了我们所有人
To all of us.
我才得知  柯丽丝汀小姐
I just found out, Miss Kringle left town
和多尔蒂警官一起离开了这里
with Officer Dougherty.
她和多尔蒂一起离开了哥谭
She left Gotham with Dougherty?
但他家暴啊
But he was abusive.
爱情嘛
Love.
真没想到
I-I'm... I'm stunned.
你要接吗
Do you need to get that?
不  不用
No. I don't think so.
爱德
Oh, Ed...
你一定很难过
you must be devastated.
现在  我只想集中精神工作
Right now, I'm just trying to focus on the job.
你要想找人谈谈  尽管找我
Well, let me know if you ever want to talk.
谢谢  有你这话就够了
Thank you. That means a lot.
什么事
Yes?
辣芥末在哪
Where is the spicy mustard?
最好不是被你吃完了...
You better not have finished...
当我没说
Never mind.
茜尔薇  你还好吗  发生了什么事
Silver, are you okay? What happened?
我只给你一个机会
You have one chance.
放我们走
You let us go...
我叫你开口
You talk...
你再说
when I tell you to.
明白没
Understand?
好了  告诉你们  我们在城外
Now... So you know, we are outside of the city,
绝对没人听得到你们求救
and there is absolutely no one to hear you scream,
只有我能听到
except me.
你为韦恩集团的人做事吗
You work for the people inside Wayne Enterprises.
不管谁是你老板...
Whoever's paying you...
再说一遍...
Again...
我叫你开口你再说
you talk when I tell you to.
我老板听说
Now, my employers have heard
你在考虑把你的公司股份
that you are thinking of selling your company shares
卖给这小姑娘的叔叔
to the uncle of this one?
这不是什么好事
That's not good.
但不是抓你们来的原因
But not why we're here.
主要问题是  最近有人打探...
The issue is: someone's been nosing into the deaths...
托马斯...
of Thomas...
和玛莎·韦恩遇害的事
and poor Martha Wayne.
不知是谁呢
And I wonder who.
开玩笑的
Kidding.
我们都知道是金发姑娘的叔叔
We know it was blondie's uncle.
我的任务呢...就是查明
So... I've been tasked to find out
亲爱的叔叔都跟小布鲁斯·韦恩说过什么
what dear old uncle told little Bruce Wayne.
什么都没说
Nothing.
盖勒文什么都没告诉我
Galavan didn't tell me anything.
你以为
You think
你是孩子  我就不会打你吗
that I won't hurt you because you're a kid?
或者因为你有名
Or because you're you?
看看你妈妈和爸爸的下场吧
How'd that work out for your mummy and daddy?
这事关数十亿
There are billions at stake here.
数十亿啊
And that's with a B.
你想动手就动手吧
Do what you want to me.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
好  那就从金发妞开始下手吧
Okay, so we start with Goldilocks.
你敢动她  我发誓...
You touch her, and I swear...
你会怎样
Yeah?
我被好多厉害人物威胁过  小子  你...
I've been threatened by the best, kid, and you...
你的威胁太弱了
not exactly terrifying.
我来告诉你
Now, let me tell you
接下来会怎么样吧
how this is going to go.
稍后
In a minute,
我会带你们中的一位
I'm gonna take one of you
到里屋去
into the back
开始切掉你们的手指
and start cutting off your fingers.
你们会招的
And you're gonna talk.
我在这行混了有些年头了
I've been doing this a very, very long time,
人人都会招的
and everyone talks.
除非你们特别喜欢戴连指手套
So... unless you're really into wearing mittens,
这是你们最后的机会了
this is your last chance.
西奥·盖勒文知道什么
What does Theo Galavan know?
好吧
Okey-dokey.
我们走
Let's go.
不要  不要  不要
No, no, no, no, no!
-不要  等下  停下  -不要
- No, wait, stop! Stop, stop, stop! - No!
茜尔薇  你得告诉他
Silver, you have to tell him.
我会履行承诺的  我保证  求你了
I'll hold my side of the deal, I promise. Please.
求你了  我保证
Please. I promise.
但我叔叔什么都没跟我说
But my uncle didn't tell me anything.
但你给我留言了
But you left me a message.
我的任务是拖住你  到今晚上
I was supposed to keep you busy till this evening.
他确定自己能脱罪
He's sure he's going to be freed.
然后他会说服你卖掉自己的公司
Then he'll convince you to sell your company.
对不起  布鲁斯
I'm sorry, Bruce.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
真的吗
Really?
我不知道
I don't!
真可惜
That's a pity.
-不  -不
- No. - No!
小子
Kid.
不要  求你了
No! Please.
小子  你女朋友不怎样啊
Kid. You really need better taste in women.
不要
No!
不要  布鲁斯
Stop! Bruce!
你还以为已经见识过哥谭最后的珍宝了
Just when you think Gotham's shown her last jewel,
她又再次让你惊艳
she reveals herself like a flower.
你在瞎比喻
You're mixing metaphors.
我在下水道里
I'm in a freakin' sewer.
你听到声音了吗
You hear something?
有人声
A voice.
我认识这家伙
I know this bum.
雇佣打手
Muscle for hire.
看看额头上的手指画
Check out the finger painting on the forehead.
码头的死者也一样
Victim at the port had the same thing.
是一种赐福
Like a blessing.
凶手肯定没跑远
Whoever did this can't be too far away.
我们应该...
We should...
哈维
Harvey!
不不不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no...
拜托  别掉下来  撑住
Please, please, don't. Hold.
他需要救护车
He needs an ambulance.
我们得弄醒他  逼他开口
We got to wake him up, make him talk.
拿感受不到疼痛的宗教疯子能有什么办法
Religious fanatic who doesn't feel pain? What's our angle?
这些疯子杀了八个人  不管他们想干什么
These nut-jobs have killed eight people. Whatever their plan is,
不管盖勒文想干什么  他们马上要动手了
whatever Galavan's up to, it is happening now.
我们得逼他开口
We make him talk.
我们怎么办  折磨他吗
What are we gonna do, torture him?
威胁不救他吗  他不会在乎的
Threaten to let him die? He wouldn't care.
这下面没有信号
There's no signal down here.
我去呼叫支援  但我得上去
I'll call in, but I got to go up.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊
God!
审判...
The day...
日
...of reckoning.
审判日  兄弟
The day... of reckoning, brother.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
别的不说
Well, if nothing else,
今天让我对小富二代增添了一丝尊敬
today has given me a newfound respect for boy billionaires.
小家伙比看上去骨头要硬多了
Kid's tougher than he looks.
什么都不知道
Didn't know a damn thing.
你杀了他吗
Did you kill him?
不  还没有
No, not yet.
但接下来要取决于你了
But the rest is kind of up to you.
我说过了...
I told you...
我叔叔什么都没告诉我
my uncle didn't tell me anything.
你还要坚持这种说法吗
Are you gonna stick to that story?
这是事实
It's the truth.
布鲁斯  对不起  我什么都不知道
Bruce, I'm sorry! I don't know anything!
你知道吗
You know what?
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
韦恩家那孩子...
The Wayne kid--
他还有点骨气
he's got some sap in him.
但是你...
But you...
有时候看到一个人  就觉得她不顺眼
You know when you meet someone, and you just don't click?
这就是我对你的感觉
That's the way I feel about you.
所以这对我来说会简单多了
That's why this is gonna be so much easier.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我要让你说实话
I'm gonna make sure that you are telling the truth.
你敢动我  我叔叔就会宰了你
Touch me, and my uncle will have you gutted.
你爱的每一个人都会尖叫着死去
Every person you love will die screaming.
我受够了
I've had enough of this.
马上放了我
Let me go. Now!
你好啊
Well, hello!
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet ya!
我就知道刚刚那不是真正的你
I knew there was someone hiding in there.
你是又聋又丑吗
Are you deaf as well as ugly?
我说了  放了我
I said... let me go!
我听到了  公主
I heard you, princess.
你干什么
What are you doing?
住手
Stop!
马龙  那人叫马龙
Malone! It's Malone!
-什么  -马龙  他叫这个
- What's that? - Malone. That's the name.
这就是杀死了布鲁斯·韦恩父母的人
The man who killed Bruce Wayne's parents.
你叔叔的确告诉你了啊
So your uncle did tell you.
不是今天  早告诉我了
Not today. Before.
他最初得知时就告诉我了
When he first found out.
马龙是个常见的姓氏
Malone's a very common name.
他名字首字母是M
His first name begins with "M."
我只知道这些
That's all I know.
住手
Stop!
知道吗
You know what?
我相信你
I believe you.
行了吧
Are we good?
行了
Yes.
可以了
We're good.
记得我吗
Remember me?
那个下贱胚子
The gutter trash?
布鲁斯  怎么回事
Bruce... what's happening?
你觉得呢  白痴
What does it look like, dummy?
我们骗了你
We tricked you.
不过  要是我说了算
Though, if it was up to me,
你就会少几根手指了
you would've lost a few fingers.
你心软了吗  汤姆
Going soft, Tom?
小猫
Cat.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你  韦恩先生
Thank you, Mr. Wayne.
跟你做生意很愉快
Pleasure doing business.
那几个耳刮子抱歉了
Sorry about the slaps.
你俩应付她没问题吧
Now are you two gonna be okay with this one,
还是需要我...
or would you like me to, uh...?
不用  没事的
Nah. We're cool.
韦恩先生  再会了  我们走
Mr. Wayne. Boys.
你现在大概觉得很困惑
You're probably very confused right now.
脑子里大概有无数个问题
Probably have a million questions going through your head.
布鲁斯  求你
Bruce, please...
闭嘴
Be quiet!
我信任你  茜尔薇
I trusted you, Silver.
即便是在你叔叔被捕之后
Even after your uncle was arrested,
我还是相信你是我的朋友
I still believed you were my friend.
最终  是塞琳娜让我看清了你的面目
It was finally Selina who convinced me otherwise.
我就从没信过你那套戏码
I never bought your stupid act.
她闯进了你的公寓
She broke into your apartment,
找到了一份关于我的资料
found the file you had on me.
显然  你是被派来说服我卖掉公司的
It was clear that you'd been sent to push me to sell my company,
你一家人都不是好人
that your entire family was corrupt,
但我还是得查明
but I still had to find out
你叔叔对我父母的凶案掌握的情况
what your uncle knew about my parents' murder.
现在我知道了
Now I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
布鲁斯  等等
Bruce! Wait.
那个名字不是真的
That name wasn't real.
只是我编的  好阻止他
It was just something I made up to stop him.
真有意思
That's funny.
你自己被架在刀上
You only made it up
你才编了个名字
when you were under the knife,
布鲁斯被折磨时却什么都没说
not when Bruce was getting tortured.
你个小婊子
You little bitch, I'll...
来啊
Please.
动手试试啊
Try it.
你说对我叔叔了
You're right about my uncle.
他就是大家说的那样
He's everything everyone says.
还更糟
Worse.
如果被他发现我向你泄密了
When he finds out what I told you,
他会杀了我的
he'll kill me.
你装作是我的朋友
You pretended to be my friend.
再见了  茜尔薇
Good-bye, Silver.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
你今天跟我说的话
The things you told me today.
我相信了你
I believed you.
是啊  要的就是这样
Yes. That was the point.
布鲁斯  你不能这么对我
Bruce, you can't do this.
这不像你
It isn't you.
那是你这么想
That's what you think.
但你错了
But you're wrong.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
Bruce!
布鲁斯
救护车
The ambulance is...
喝吧  兄弟
Drink... brother.
看不到
Can't... see.
你受伤了
You're hurt.
别动
Lie still.
警察呢
The police?
死了  我们及时赶到了
Dead. We got here just in time.
九人之血
The blood of the nine...
将洗刷罪孽
Shall wash away the sin.
我已经完成了任务  兄弟
I fulfilled my task, brother.
只剩下
All that remains
那小子了
is the son.
是的  那小子
Yes. The son.
赐福我吧  兄弟
Give me your blessing, brother.
求你
Please.
哥谭之子
The Son of Gotham
必死无疑
shall die,
哥谭
and the city
将得到净化
shall be cleansed.
警探  那位...
Detective, where is the...?
什么
What?
你是谁
Who are you?!
哥谭市警局  你被捕了
GCPD. You're under arrest.
送他去医院  看看能不能问出什么来
Take him to the hospital, see if you can get anything from him.
我得去见巴恩斯
I got to see Barnes.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
布鲁斯  你在吗
Bruce, you in here?
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce?
小布少爷  你在吗
Master B, you here?
你在擅闯民宅
You're trespassing.
我在找布鲁斯·韦恩
I'm looking for Bruce Wayne.
他不接电话
Now, he's not answering his phone.
不在家  不在学校
He's not home, he's not at school.
我猜  你跟你那个贱丫头侄女在一起呢
My guess, he's with that snotty little niece of yours.
抱歉
Sorry.
我建议你赶紧离开
Now, I suggest you leave
趁你还可以
while you still can.
看来你也挺有两下子啊
I see you're a bit of a player, are you?
那好吧  塔比
As it were then, Tabby.
大坏蛋盖勒文下命令  你就蹦来跳去
Big bad Galavan barks the orders, and you scamper around,
叼死兔子给他
bringing home dead rabbits,
换他拍拍你的脑袋  表示满意吗
so you might get a little pat on the head?
如果我把你变没了  他会怎么办呢
I wonder what he'd do if I just disappeared you.
老实说  我觉得他不会在意的
Honestly, I don't think he'd care.
如果我得知  那孩子出了什么事
If I learn anything has happened to that little boy,
我们就会知道他会不会在意了
we'll find out, won't we?
够了
Stop it!
告诉你  我说的是实话
For the record, I was telling the truth.
我真不知道布鲁斯·韦恩在哪
I have no idea where Bruce Wayne is.
但我会告诉他你在打听
But I'll tell him you were asking.
丹特先生  你方证人
Mr. Dent, your witness.
詹姆斯市长
So, Mayor James...
抱歉  丹特先生
Excuse me, Mr. Dent.
你是说前市长吧
I think you mean former mayor.
我只是一名哥谭公民了
I'm just a citizen of Gotham...
只是来说出实话
here to tell the truth.
詹姆斯先生
Mr. James...
麻烦你告诉我们
...if you could begin by telling us
你今年10月是在哪度过的
where you spent the month of October this year.
你去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
布洛克和我抓住了一名僧侣
Bullock and I captured one of the monks.
我是对的
I was right.
他们在完成某种仪式
They're completing some sort of ritual
想要净化哥谭的罪孽
to cleanse the city of sin.
他们还剩一个人要杀
They have one victim left.
并称之为哥谭之子
They're calling him the Son of Gotham.
他们提到盖勒文了吗
Did they say anything about Galavan?
-我没有被西奥·盖勒文绑架  -没有吧
- I was not kidnapped by Theo Galavan. - They didn't, did they?
安静
Quiet!
詹姆斯先生  请重复你的话
Mr. James, please repeat what you said.
西奥·盖勒文没有绑架我
Theo Galavan did not kidnap me.
法官大人  证人遭受了...
Your Honor, the witness has suffered...
请说明  先生
Please explain yourself, sir.
你为什么撒谎
Why did you lie?
是谁囚禁了你
Who held you captive?
是奥斯瓦尔德·科波特  企鹅
Oswald Cobblepot, the Penguin.
他恨西奥·盖勒文
He hates Theo Galavan.
他多次企图杀他
He tried to kill him multiple times.
是他告诉我该说什么
He told me what to say.
他对我做出可怕的威胁
He threatened me with terrible things.
-他撒谎  -戈登  戈登
- He's lying! - Gordon! Gordon!
戈登警探  请安静
Detective Gordon, silence!
-戈登  -法官大人
- Gordon! - Your Honor,
我要求马上释放我的当事人
I move my client be released at once.
法官大人  检方要求休庭  进一步...
Your Honor, the State requests a recess to further...
安静  詹姆斯先生  你知道你宣了誓吧
Quiet. Mr. James, you do realize you are under oath?
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
Oswald Cobblepot...
他折磨我  把我的脑袋锁进箱子里
tortured me, put my head in a box.
他逼我撒谎
He made me lie.
我很抱歉
I'm so very, very sorry.
鉴于詹姆斯先生的证词  以及检方
In light of Mr. James' testimony and the complete absence of
完全不能提供其他任何证据
any other evidence provided by the State,
我宣布释放西奥·盖勒文
I hereby order Theo Galavan released
并撤销对其的指控
and the case against him dismissed.
-法官大人  -别  吉姆
- Your Honor! - No, Jim.
我们没办法
There's nothing we can do.
法官大人  我能说几句话吗
Your Honor, may I say a few words?
我觉得可以
I think that's only fair.
我想说
I'd just like to state that...
我对戈登警探和哥谭市警局毫无埋怨
I harbor no ill will toward Detective Gordon and the GCPD.
他们尽了职
They did their jobs.
他们仍是我的英雄
They're still my heroes.
怎么样  戈登警探
What do you say, Detective Gordon?
我们可以一起向前进  拯救这座破碎
Can we move forward together to fix this broken,
但美丽的城市吗
beautiful city?
你个混蛋  你个混蛋
You son of a bitch! You're a son of a bitch!
我会逮住你的
I'm gonna get you!
把他带出去
Get him out of here!
行了  放开我
Ah, come on, get your hands off of me!
放松  我们不是要逮捕你
Relax. We're not arresting you.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred?
他大概出去找我了
He's probably out looking for me.
谢谢你  塞琳娜
Thank you, Selina.
如果不是你  我肯定做不到
I couldn't have done this without you.
我就是高兴那个两面派的小婊子得到报应了
I was just glad to see the two-faced bitch get served.
你现在打算怎么办
What are you gonna do now?
你要告诉警察  还是自己去找这个马龙
You gonna tell the cops or look for this Malone guy yourself?
老实说  我还没想那么远呢
Honestly, I haven't thought that far ahead.
那么  她去找她叔叔之前
So, when you whispered to her
你对她低语了什么
b-before she went to her uncle, what did you say?
你想知道我说了什么
You want to know what I said.
你如果不想告诉我  那我就走
Hey, if you don't want to tell me, then I can leave.
我跟她说  我从没遇见过她这样的人
I told her I've never met anyone like her.
我说我敢把性命交给她
I told her I trusted her with my life.
还有
And that...
我与她之间的羁绊
I felt tied to her in a way that I...
我解释不清  但又不会改变
couldn't explain, but wouldn't change.
永远不会
Ever.
最好的骗子  总是说真话
The best liars always tell the truth.
这是真话吗
That was true?
是的
Yes.
但说的不是她
Just not about her.
我要偷你一辆车
I'm... I'm gonna steal one of your cars to...
开去城里  行吗
take to the city. Cool?
好啊
Sure.
你在改变  这是好事
It's good you're changing.
但
Just...
别变得太多了
don't change too much.
你为什么要留下她的眼镜啊
Why did you keep her glasses to begin with?
我说了
I told y...
我爱过柯林格小姐
I loved Miss Kringle.
丢掉吧
Just get rid of them.
汤普金斯医生起疑了
Dr. Thompkins is suspicious.
真业余
Amateurs.
盖布  我给你这个地址
Gabe, when I gave you this address,
不是叫你跑来看望
I was not inviting pop-ins.
盖勒文被释放了
Galavan's been let go.
他人呢
Where is he?
我的天
My, my.
仅仅一天  情况变化这么大
What a difference a day brings.
在这儿  你是囚徒  而我是自由的
Here, you're the prisoner and I'm free.
命运之轮啊
Fortune's wheel.
不停转动
Turn, turn.
这些警察
These cops?
是好人  会见风使舵
Good men who can tell which way the wind's blowing.
好了  我们时间有限
Now, we have a very small window.
我还有地方要去  你还要死
I have places to be, you have to die,
但我知道  你肯定有好多问题
but I know you must have questions, so...
那些僧侣
The monks.
他们为你工作吗
They... work for you?
几世纪来
For centuries,
圣杜马修会一直保护我们家族
the Order of St. Dumas has protected my family.
他们是这黑暗世界的一丝光明
They have been a light in a dark world.
告诉你个秘密啊
Shall I tell you a secret?
西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan
只是个面具
is a mask.
我姓杜马
My name is Dumas,
我们家族从平地建立起了这座城市
and my family built this city out of nothing.
但我们遭到了背叛
But we were betrayed,
被驱逐  遗忘
driven out, erased.
原来是为了这个
So that's all this is about?
复仇
Revenge?
不
No.
是为了赎罪
This is about atonement.
建立哥谭的大地
The ground that Gotham is built on
因我先辈受到的屈辱而被荼毒
is poisoned by the wrongs done to my forefathers.
我要改变这一点
I will change that.
通过随机杀掉九个人吗
By killing nine random people?
你疯了
You're insane.
我明白你为什么会这么想
I can see why you'd think so.
仪式性血祭
Ritual blood sacrifices,
一群穿袍子的家伙
bunch of guys in robes
吟唱着预言
chanting prophesies.
的确挺...
It's a bit too...
但信仰  这才是重要的  警探
But belief itself-- that's what matters, Detective.
信仰给人力量
Belief gives strength,
目标
purpose.
而且受害者并不都是随机的
And not all the victims are random.
哥谭之子
The Son of Gotham.
再见了  詹姆斯
Good-bye, James.
没有你  我真是做不到
I couldn't have done it without you.
不管了
Ah, what the hell.
我还有点时间  把他放下来
I have a few minutes. Cut him loose.
好了  吉姆  拼力一试吧
All right, Jim, give it your best shot.
拯救哥谭啊
Save Gotham.
杀了他
Kill him.
慢慢来
Don't make it quick.
阿尔弗雷德  是你吗
Alfred? Is that you?
你绝不会相信我发现了什么
You won't believe what I learned...
抱歉
Sorry.
不是阿尔弗雷德
Not Alfred.
你好  吉姆
Hello, Jim.
算你走运  盖布叫人跟踪了盖勒文
Lucky for you, Gabe had people following Galavan.
好了
Now...
他在哪
where is he?
盖勒文在哪
Where's Galavan?!
告诉我
Tell me!
盖勒文在哪
Where is Galavan?!
你有勇有谋  孩子
You've shown mettle and ingenuity, my boy.
但那都过去了
But that's all done with.
你想要什么
What do you want?
当然是你的命了
Why, your life, of course.